Julianne VanWagenen

<u>jvanwagenen.github.io</u> | Cambridge, MA, USA | +1 517 505 5057 | jmvanwag@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Graduate-level program and content manager; ex-university instructor; researcher; webmaster; project manager; & book/journal managing editor; detail-oriented self-starter who enjoys and excels at problem solving in a team environment; 15+ years experience in web design & ed program creation/coordination

SKILLS

Interpersonal Communication Team building & Collaboration Academic Research and Writing Attention to Detail Project Management Strategic & Organizational Planning Meaningful Goal-driven Content Creation Problem Solving Qualitative & Quantitative Research Presentations & Public Speaking Adobe Suite, HTML, CSS Foreign Languages

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

HBS Online, Harvard Business Analytics Program

Online Learning Manager

Boston, MA July 2022 – Present

- Manage courses and seminars on an online course platform: includes liaising with faculty and TFs, updating course content, coordinating online live sessions, office hours, and simulations across the term, managing the courses in Slack
- Create videos using Photoshop and Premiere as needed: includes videos for social media posts, new faculty videos for the online orientation course, a peer-learning orientation video series for new students
- Create and manage much of the supplemental programming HBAP offers: including Startup Academy, an 8-week online course (2023; created with a team and executed); HBAP Pitch Competition, a term-long program with a mentor series, pitch workshops, submission round, live online finals, and LinkedIn Live event for the winner (2023-24; updated and executed); HBAP Summer Programming, a 2-month set of programming for all 1000+ current and past HBAP participants (2023-24; created and executed); Career Services webinar series (2024; updated and executed); D^3 Cubie Awards and Ceremony (2024; worked with a team to create and execute on a short timeline)
- Act as the accessibility lead for the program: includes remediating videos and slide decks, creating audio descriptions and elaborated transcripts, and working with program partners to implement all updates on in the online courses
- Work with a team, term over term, to plan and execute HBAP's in-person 3-day immersions on HBS Campus

Harvard University

Postdoctoral Fellow

Cambridge, MA

January 2022 – July 2022

- Book project proposal selected from a wide group of candidates from around the world
- Work on research and publishing related to countercultural song, modern mythologies, mass tourism, and travel ethics; have published and peer-reviewed book and articles (see below).

Pirandello in Translation - Stories for a Year

Web Developer, Translator (pirandellointranslation.org)

2021 – Present

- Designed and built the book-project website, which hosts a growing number of original Pirandello translations
- Worked with a team to create project goals, wire-frame design, take feedback, and build consensus to finalize
- Continue to work with a team to coordinate translation and presentation of digital publication of translations

Pirandello Society of America

Board of Directors

2019 - Present

- Help organize the scheduling and program-details for our quarterly board-member meetings
- Present and lead discussions: such as moving general membership payment online; website renovation; website design; updating membership policies and costs; hosting our journal archive online; organizing annual events
- Work with content editors to clearly communicate complex issues and reach board consensus
- Work with content editors to elaborate and enact all society projects from inception to delivery (new membership payment system; digital archive; annual journal production; printing costs and options; etc.)

Pirandello Society of America

Web Developer (pirandellosociety.org)

2019 - 2023

- Designed and built the literary-society and academic-journal website
- Worked with a team to create project goals, wire-frame design, take feedback, and build consensus to finalize

The Pirandello Society Annual Journal

2017 - 2023Managing Editor

- Design and build each the annual journal using InDesign; create cover designs in Gimp
- Copy-edit the content and formatting for the entire journal
- Work with the content editors to come to a consensus on cover design and other formatting questions
- Prepare journal for printer; communicate with printer across the entire process to assure print accuracy

Tsinghua University Instructor, Thesis Advisor

Beijing, China Fall 2018 - Fall 2021

Created and taught courses in the Institute of World Literatures and Cultures: "Journey to Italy: Travel Writing since the Grand Tour", "Rereading the Divine Comedy with Borges", "Postcolonial Literature in the 1900s"

- Instituted an initiative in sophomore seminars that helped students to excel in academic writing
- Helped organize the curriculum of IWLC in terms of pedagogical and content goals and program continuity
- Organized a Graduate School Application workshop; organized workshops, mentored students one-on-one
- Advised senior-theses; organized time, set deliverable dates; advised on research, citational styles, clarity

University of Southern California Lecturer

Los Angeles, CA Spring 2018

Taught 3 courses in Italian language, worked with a team to create and grade bi-weekly assessments

Worked with a team to create a community-based component to courses; facilitated weekly language table

Milan and Siena: Harvard Summer School Study Abroad

Milan and Siena, Italy

Coordinator, Instructor

Summer 2016, Summer 2017

- Worked on a team to develop and teach the language-program courses for a new study-abroad program
- Worked with a team to organize the housing, field trips, events, reservations for a group of 30 undergraduates
- Led 2 sections of 8-credit Aesthetics & Ethics course taught during the summer abroad
- Handled all translation, documentation, and emergency issues for study-abroad students

Monad Media Cambridge, MA

Owner, Project Manager

2014 - 2017

- Founded company that provided economical web development to academic projects
- Worked with creative teams in Harvard GSAS and Libraries to create wire frames and manage web development
- Led project management, including timelines, deadlines, cost analysis, bug fixes, etc., for all projects

metaLAB (at) Harvard

Cambridge, MA 2013 - 2017

Project Manager, Principal Investigator

- Participated as a creative lead in metaLAB principal meetings; wrote grant applications for various projects
- Worked with a team of professors to create interdisciplinary courses (offered FAS and GSD); created syllabi, created and taught innovate discussion-sections/studios; organized summer developer workshops and new digital-humanities projects
- Project manager for curarium.com; managed developer team using Redmine, worked with advisors at the Berkman Klein Center, tracked deadlines and bug fixes, presented platform at conferences and workshops

Harvard University Cambridge, MA

Course Developer, Instructor, Thesis Advisor

2013 - 2017

- Developed and taught courses in in the Romance Languages and Literatures department
- Wrote grant applications; won 2017 Elson Family Arts Initiative Fund to Support Arts in Curricula
- Won the Harvard University Department of Romance Languages and Literatures Teaching Prize in 2016
- Won the Derek Bok Center for Teaching and Learning Certificate of Excellence for every semester I was eligible
- Organized Chiasmi Graduate Student Conference in 2013
- Presented at panels or invited talks and/or organized and chaired panels at over 20 conferences and events

Dudley House Library Cambridge, MA 2012 - 2017Head Librarian

- Hired and managed a team of between 5 and 8 librarians; managed library with team

Harvard University Cambridge, MA Doctoral Researcher 2011 - 2017

- Completed my doctoral work on time and with a successful dissertation that was published in 2023
- 2013-14 Video Coordinator for Colloquium series; coordinated and managed production of video interviews
- Copy-edited various projects, for example, Johanna Drucker's Graphesis (2014)
- Worked as a translator for the Italian cantautori in Translation website theitaliansong.com

The American in Italia Magazine

Columnist

Rome, Italy 2009 - 2014

Met monthly deadlines, worked with editor to revise, copy edit; published over 40 articles (see below for link)

Physical Chemistry Department, Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI 2009 - 2011

Web Developer, Data Analyst

- Created a website (Dreamweaver) for the PI's research project on the dipole moment of white-dwarf stars
- Wrote programs in Terminal that ran on the university super computer and simulated how molecules would act when put under the intense atmospheric pressure of a white-dwarf star; collected/organized all post-run data

EDUCATION

Harvard University - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences

Cambridge, MA

PhD, Italian Studies

September 2011 - May 2017

DePaul University - Honors College

Chicago, IL

BA, with High Honors, Double Major in Italian Studies and English Literature

September 2002 - March 2006

Additional Study L'università Roma Tre, Biology Program

Roma, Italy September 2007 - June 2008

LANGUAGES

English (native), Italian (near-native), Spanish (intermediate), French (basic)

SOFTWARE

Adobe Creative Suite (Premiere, Express, Dreamweaver, InDesign, Photoshop (Gimp)); Canvas; Redmine; Excel; Atom (HTML and CSS); GitHub

MEDIA COVERAGE

Research Featured in Volpe, Andrea. "Being Human Now: How Innovative Methods and Contemporary Concerns are Helping Humanities Scholars Re-Envision the Past and Imagine the Future." Colloguy. Spring 2016. 12-17.